Guide to the Trent history of medicine manuscripts collection, [1588?], 1661-1994 and undated, bulk 1750-1980
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Trent History of Medicine manuscript collection [1588?], 1661-1994 and undated, bulk 1750-1980, (780 collections; approximately 6,000 items)
  - Roux, Emile, 1853-1933. Papers, 1908-1926 and undated, (4 items) (Box 10)
    French bacteriologist and director of the Pasteur Institute, Paris. Two letters and an autograph manuscript, signed, convey Roux's suspicions that the removal of Dr. Remlinger, the French head of the Constantinople branch of the Pasteur Institute, was due to German intrigue. There is also a note to M. Ernst Fritz Katz.
  - Roux, Fernand. Letter, 1885, Sept. 10, (1 item) (Box 10)
    French physician. Letter (ALS). Asks if papers submitted for contests of the Société de médecine are returned after the announcements of the awards.
  - Royle, J.T. Manuscript, undated, (1 item) (Box 10)
    Physician. Manuscript (AMS). Royle's detailed report to Adam, Secretary to the Medical Board, Fort William, of the death from cholera of surgeon Henry Cavell.
  - Rush, William. Note, undated, (1 item) (Box 10)
    Prescription written on small piece of paper, "for Wm. Edw. Thornton" or "Thorndon." Seems to contain calomel and a sulphur compound. Unclear why creator name is William Rush - his name does not appear on note.
  - Russell, Charles. Document, 1763, Feb. 18, (1 item) (Box 10)
    Physician. Autograph document, signed. An itemized statement of the amount owed by the Province of the Massachusetts Bay to Charles Russell for services rendered.
  - Russell, William Howard. Note, 1864 Aug. 24, (1 item) (Box 10)
    London attorney. Inquiry to an unknown person about when "plates" will be ready. His home address is at top: Summer Place.
  - Ruston, Thomas, ca. 1739-1804. Document, 1765, Nov. 26, (1 item) (Box 10)
    Physician of Philadelphia. Holograph document, signed. Diploma granted by Edinburgh University, signed by Alexander Monro, William Cullen, and Alexander Monro, Jr., among others.
  - Sée, Germain, 1818-1896. Papers, [After 1840], (2 items) (Box 10)
    French physician. Notes (ANS). Prescribes a diuretic diet and daily sea baths.
  - Sabatier, Raphaël Bienvenu, 1732-1811. Note, [Between 1750 and 1811?], (1 item) (Box 10)
  - St. Thomas's Hospital. Document, [Between 1775 and 1823], (1 item) (Box 10)
    Document, signed. John Mitchell petitions the Hospital for admittance. The Hospital receives the promise of John Haighton, physician, to supply the patient with clean body linen weekly and to remove the body at his expense, if the patient should die within the Hospital's care.
  - St. Vincent, John Jervis, Viscount, 1735-1823. Papers, 1796-1800, (59 items) (Box 10)
    Admiral of the Blue and Commander-in-Chief, British Navy. Papers relate to the British naval hospital at Gibraltar and include weekly reports on the state of the hospital at Port Mahon, signed by John Gray, surgeon; list of gratuitous medicines, signed by Gray; account of lemons issued, signed by Gray; returns of the sick and wounded, signed by J. Gardiner, surgeon; reports on the state of the naval hospital at Gibraltar, signed by John Weir and Edward Vaughan; lists of hospital expenditures, and correspondence. Correspondents include St. Vincent, Captain Duckworth, Weir, Vaughan, R. Blair, W. Gibbons, J. Johnston, and Gilbert Blane, Henry Semple, from the French surgeons on the Luise Cherie, and printed material.
  - Salmon, Frederick, 1796-1868. Papers, 1864-1867, (2 items) (Box 11)
    British surgeon. Letters (ALS). Salmon writes to a Miss Acton, a former patient, referring to his health and to the election of assistant surgeons at St. Mark's Hospital.
  - Salisbury, Connecticut. Records,, 1803-1865, (21 items) (Box 11)
    A variety of early documents recording payments to various doctors for their services for the town and medical treatments for townspeople, among them "paupers." There are quite a few references to smallpox. There is a mention of a board of health.
  - Sanarelli, Giuseppe, 1864-1940. Letter, 1901, Oct. 4, (1 item) (Box 11)
    Italian pathologist and hygienist. Letter (ALS). Declines invitation to become a member of the National League, "Pro-Italia".
  - Sandwith, Humphry, 1822-1881. Papers, 1864 and undated, (2 items) (Box 11)
    English physician and historian. Notes (ANS). Sandwith writes to his publisher regarding the date of publication of his new book and to a Miss Pike regarding the dates of his departure from and return to England.
  - Sargent, Nathaniel. Receipt of payment, 1718, April, (1 item) (Box 11)
    Small note recording the payment for services.
  - Satterlee, Richard Sherwood, 1798-1880. Letter, 1847, July 30, (1 item) (Box 11)
    U.S. Army surgeon. Letter (ALS). Satterlee appeals to Worth, informing him that horses intended for the ambulance train were taken by cavalry company captain Philip Kearny.
  - Saunders, William, 1743-1817. Note, [Between 1800 and 1817], (1 item) (Box 11)
    English physician and chemist. Note (ANS). Requests that bearer be given a copy of his work on mineral waters, as well as his book on the liver. Note is attached to short biographical sketch.
  - Sayer, John Lathrop, b. 1819. Papers, 1833-1872, (13 items) (Box 11)
    Patient at the New York St. Asylum, Utica, New York. Papers consist of three types of material: correspondence, loose manuscript leaves, and manuscript notebooks. Correspondence consists of letters written by Sayer, his wife, Sarah A. Sayer, and the Superintendent at the Asylum, John Gray, during Sayer's stay at the Asylum. Loose manuscripts consist of miscellaneous notes, a poem, Sayer's teacher certification, and the school lists of both Sayer and his wife, then Sarah Ann Bennet. Notebooks: "Sketches of Life" (a journal, tp., 23 pp., 1842-1859); "A Book Intended for Writings" (notebook of essays and poems, tp., 23 pp., 1837); and an algebra notebook (tp., 85 pp., 1833) with notes on town bonds at the end (3 pp., 1872).
  - Sayre, Lewis Albert, 1820-1900. Note, [Between 1850 and 1900], (1 item) (Box 11)
    U.S. orthopedic surgeon. Note (ANS). Introduces Dr. Grant, a Canadian surgeon.
  - Schönlein, Johann Lukas, 1793-1864. Note, 1856, June 26, (1 item) (Box 11)
    German clinician. Note (ANS). Informs addressee that he will be away for a few days.
  - Schenck, Peter V. Letter, 1862, May 21, (1 item) (Box 11)
    Civil War Union Army surgeon. Letter (ALS). Schenck informs Brinton that the medicines he requested have been dispatched, speaks disparagingly of "Sanitarians" and "Nightingales", and refers to the hospital boats at the Landing.
  - Schleich, Carl Ludwig, 1859-1922. Note, 1902, Feb. 21, (1 item) (Box 11)
    German surgeon. Note (ANS). Informs addressee that he will be unable to meet as planned.
  - Schomberg, Isaac, 1714-1780. Papers, 1747-1773, (8 items) (Box 11)
    English physician. Papers relate to Schomberg's petition and appeal to become a member of the Royal College of Physicians. Schomberg was summoned by the President and Censors of the College, to be examined for a license. He declined to do so and his practice was interdicted. Schomberg then commissioned Sir George Lee to test the legality of this decision.
  - Schulze, Franz Eilhard, 1840-1921. Letter, 1901, Nov. 18, (1 item) (Box 11)
    German zoologist. Letter (ALS). Sends a question of nomenclature for publication in the Zoologischer Anzeiger.
  - Schuyler, Philip John, 1733-1804. Letter, 1801, May 2, (1 item) (Box 11)
    Commander of the Northern Department of New York during the American Revolution. Letter (ALS). Schuyler, a chronic sufferer of gout, gives his case history and writes of Samuel Stringer's prescribed treatment against gout, the inhalation of oxygen.
  - Sears, John. Document, 1845, June 31, (1 item) (Box 11)
    Physician. Holograph receipt, signed by John S. Jewett for payments received for Dr. John Sears from the town of Sharon.
  - Semelaigne, René. Papers, 1926, (3 items) (Box 11)
    French medical historian. Letters (ALS). Semelaigne and Henri Colin write about plans for the celebration of the centennial of the death of Philippe Pinel. Semelaigne was Pinel's grandnephew and head of the centenary committee.
  - Senter, Isaac, 1753?-1799. Document, 1792, Oct. 5, (1 item) (Box 11)
    Rhode Island army surgeon. Holograph receipt, signed by Senter for payment received from Capt. Benjamin Fry for medical treatment and medicine between 1787 and 1792.
  - Sewall, Thomas, 1786 or 7-1845. Papers, 1826-1835, (6 items) (Box 11)
    Physician of Washington, D. C. and professor at Columbia College. Letters (ALS). Sewell writes to Rev. David Benedict, on fundraising efforts for the College, and to Tristam Burges, regarding the health of Burges' daughter and referring to various medical publications.
  - Shattuck, Frederick Cheever, 1847-1929. Papers, 1822-1928, (31 items) (Box 11)
    Boston physician. Letters (ALS and TLS) to Shattuck regarding Harvard Medical School history and the raising of funds for a bust of John Collins Warren (1778-1856). Notable correspondents include Frank Billings, Henry Ashbury Christian, John Miller Turpin Finney, Joel Ernest Goldthwait, Elliott Proctor Joslin, Richard Pearson Strong, Edward Wyllys Taylor, John Collins Warren (1866-1932), and Aldred Scott Warthin. Papers also include letters to the Arnold family of Paris from Shattuck's father, George Cheyne Shattuck, Jr. (1813-1893), and his grandfather, George Cheyne Shattuck (1783-1854). There is also a newspaper clipping of an obituary for G. C. Shattuck, Jr.
  - Shecut, John Linnaeus Edward Whitridge, 1770-1836. Letter, 1829, June 19, (1 item) (Box 11)
    Physician and botanist of Charleston, South Carolina. Letter (ALS). Asks whether Thacher received a parcel of books and articles sent to him by way of his neighbor.
  - Shelmerdine, A. Note, 1908, Oct. 1, (1 item) (Box 11)
    Holograph note. Accepts invitation to luncheon by the Trustees of the Johns Hopkins Hospital.
  - Shippen, William, 1736?-1808. Papers, 1786-1791, (2 items) (Box 11)
    Philadelphia physician. Letters (ALS) to an Alexander Wilcocks and a note (ANS) certifying that Jacob Hicks attended his lectures upon anatomy, surgery and midwifery.
  - Short, Charles Wilkins, 1794-1863. Note, 1841, June 1, (1 item) (Box 11)
    Physician and botanist of Kentucky. Note (ANS). Asks that Buchanan hold three parcels for him.
  - Short, S. or W. Letter, 1813, Dec. 16, (1 item) (Box 11)
    Letter (ALS). Thanks addressee for prints sent to the Princess Charlotte.
  - Sichel, Jules, 1802-1868. Papers, 1850-1860, (2 items) (Box 11)
    French ophthalmologist. Letters (ALS) to a prospective patient and a holograph prescription, signed.
  - Siebold, Eduard Caspar Jacob von, 1801-1861. Letter, 1840, July 26, (1 item) (Box 11)
    German obstetrician. Letter (ALS). Relates information on a parasite.
  - Sill, William M. Note, 1886, Apr. 15, (1 item) (Box 11)
    Physician. Note (ANS). Attests that Sill attended M. August Gaschet during the latter's illness.
  - Silliman, Benjamin, 1779-1864. Note, 1853, Sept. 28, (1 item) (Box 11)
    Physician and chemist of New Haven, Connecticut. Note (ANS). Sends autograph for Waldron's autograph collection.
  - Simpson, James Young, Sir, 1811-1870. Papers, 1835-1911 and undated, (106 items) (Box 11)
    Scottish obstetrician; introduced use of chloroform. 92 ms. leaves of Simpson's notes on obstetrics, H.A. Kelly's description of contents of notes, six items printed material, four ALS from Simpson, a holograph poem, a signed calling card, and ms notes on Simpson in Kelly's hand. In his letters, Simpson writes of acupressure, animal magnetism, smallpox, scarlet fever, classical education, the importance of physical exercise and electoral politics. Printed material relates to members of the Simpson family, including Alexander Russell Simpson and Margaret Stewart Barbour. In his notes, Simpson writes of diseases of the placenta and the fetus, of pregnancies, abortions and premature labor, and of the use of collyria in the treatment of eye diseases.
  - Sims, James, 1741-1820. Letter, 1795, May 30, (1 item) (Box 11)
    New York gynecologist. Letter (ALS). Description of his collection of books and manuscripts.
  - Sims, James Marion, 1813-1883. Papers, 1860-1867 and undated, (3 items) (Box 11)
    English obstetrician. Two letters (ALS), regarding an upcoming operation and a social call, and an autograph signature sample.
  - Singer, Charles Joseph, 1876-1960. Letter, 1921, Oct. 25, (1 item) (Box 11)
    Historian of science and medicine. Letter (TLS). Thanks Sir D'Arcy for loan of his copies of "the Leechdoms", probably referring to Thomas Oswald Cockayne's Leechdoms, Wortcunning, and Starcraft of Early England.
  - Smith, Grafton Elliot, Sir, 1871-1937. Letter, 1931, Dec. 27, (1 item) (Box 11)
    British anatomist and anthropologist. Smith argues that the feeling of shame is encouraged by the wearing of clothes and not vice versa.
  - Smith, Jerome Van Crowninshield, 1800-1879. Letter, 1842, Oct. 22, (1 item) (Box 11)
    Physician of Boston. Letter (ALS). Explains his absence at forthcoming meetings and the need to defer the lecture due from him.
  - Smith, Joseph R. Letter, [1866], Mar. 11, (1 item) (Box 11)
    Surgeon. Letter (ALS). Writes of the circumstances of the death of Grier's son in the explosion of The Miami.
  - Smith, Southwood, 1788-1861. Letter, 1839, Dec. 12, (1 item) (Box 11)
    English physician. Letter (ALS). Explains that he must defer giving his lectures on fever until the end of the course and that the fever hospital is not yet set up to receive patients.
  - Smyth, W. G. Note, 1841, Feb. 12, (1 item) (Box 11)
    English physician. Note (ANS). Certifies that Edmund Green is suffering from inflammation in the chest.
  - Spalding, Lyman, 1775-1821. Papers, 1799-1820, (34 items) (Box 11)
    New Hampshire physician and surgeon; noted for his studies on yellow fever and for the founding of the U.S. Pharmacopoeia. Letters (ALS), including two photostats. Most are addressed to Spalding. Correspondents include: Ezekiel Porter, Arthur Livermore, S. L. Mitchill, Nicholas Rousselet, B. Waterhouse, S. Ricketson, W. H. Woodward, Clement Storer, G. Richards, W. D. Peck, N. Potter, Ebenezer Lerned, J. C. Warren, C. Wistar, J. Langdon, J. A. Smith, G. C. Shattuck, H. U. Onderdonk, J. L. E. W. Shecut, J. De La Motta, William Eustis Langdon, and S. N. Trevett. Matters discussed include: the cause and prevention of yellow fever and the promotion of the Pharmacopoeia. Reference is also made to medical periodicals, e. g. The New England Journal of Medicine, The Medical Repository, and the Medical and Philosophical Journal and Review. Letters from U. Parsons, Sir Robert Perceval and M. Rouviere offer a view of European medicine, referring to J. Abernethy, Sir E. Home, Sir C. Bell, Sir W. Lawrence, W. T. Brande and J. P. Frank, and of the influence of books by Americans such as J. Gorham, P. Cleaveland and B. Rush.
  - Spare, John, 1816-1901. Letter, 1860, Sept., (1 item) (Box 12)
    Physician from New Bedford, Mass. and surgeon on board the Mahaska during the 1860s; published The Differential Calculus in 1865 (Boston). A letter from New Bedford, September 1860, titled "Copy of Dr John Spare's letter to his son John V. Spare on obscure parts of mathematical text books," follwed by and bound with, a 14-page commentary on Benjamin Pierce's mathematical treatises, with special attention to "Taylor's Theorem," prefaced by The whole manuscript was copied by a Prof. B. [Benjamin] Peirce, who is referred to in Spare's letter and is the subject of the commentary.
  - Spencer, Charles Achilles, 1813-1881. Letter, 1850, Sept. 7, (1 item) (Box 12)
    Microscopist. Letter (ALS) to a client. He quotes prices for various optical and astronomical instruments and describes the manufacture of microscopes in the mid-nineteenth century.
  - Spicey, Frederick. Letter, 1911, June 17, (1 item) (Box 12)
    A former patient of Power. Letter (ALS) expressing gratitude.
  - Spurzheim, Johann Gaspar, 1776-1832. Note, [Before 1832], (1 item) (Box 12)
    German phrenologist. Note (ANS). An autograph signature sample.
  - Standish, Myles, b. 1851. Letter, 1896, Nov. 30, (1 item) (Box 12)
    Ophthalmic surgeon of Boston and New York. Letter (ALS). Claims that Townsend cannot have a grievance against him, since he has never met Townsend.
  - Startin, James, 1851-1910. Letter, 1893, Nov. 3, (1 item) (Box 12)
    English dermatologist. Letter (ALS). Thanks the editor of a periodical for printing a notice of his lecture.
  - Stevens, Alexander Hodgdon, 1789-1869. Papers, 1839 and undated, (2 items) (Box 12)
    New York surgeon. Letters (ALS). Stevens writes a letter of recommendation for a Doctor Morgan and comments upon a case of Pott's Disease.
  - Stirling-Gilchrist, J. Papers, 1925, (2 items) (Box 12)
    British student of psychoanalysis. Two holograph manuscripts; clean copies, with some corrections. Visit to the Zurich School is a transcript (30 pp.) of interviews with members of the "Zürich School" of psychoanalysis, including C. G. Jung, Oskar Robert Pfister, Alphonse Maeder, Paul Federn, Emil Oberholzer and Eugen Bleuler. My Analysis with Freud is a transcript (44 pp.) of 15 sittings with Sigmund Freud. Stirling-Gilchrist claims to be a student of W. H. R. Rivers.
  - Stone, Robert King, 1822-1872. Letter, 1863, Aug. 3, (1 item) (Box 12)
    Ophthalmic and otological surgeon of Washington, D. C. Letter (ALS). Stone writes as a member of the Board of Health of Washington, D. C., of the dangers arising from the smoke and ashes falling on Washington from the burning of dead army animals in Virginia.
  - Stopes, Marie Carmichael, 1880-1958. Letters, 1950, (2 items) (Box 12)
    Pioneer of birth control and sexual education. Letters (ALS) from Stopes to Lord Samuel and TL, presumably from Lord Samuel, to Stopes. In this exchange, Lord Samuel declines Stopes' request to review her collection of poems, We Burn, in his upcoming presentation to the English Association.
  - Storer, David Humphreys, 1804-1891. Letter, 1829, Oct. 15, (1 item) (Box 12)
    U.S. ichthyologist and obstetrician, 1804-1890. Letter (ALS). Invites Putnam and family to attend his lectures on natural history.
  - Storer, Malcolm, b. 1862. Note, 1909, June 17, (1 item) (Box 12)
    Numismatist of Boston. Note (ANS). Thanks Norton for his gift of the medal of the Medical and Chirurgical Faculty of Maryland.
  - Stringer, Samuel, 1734-1817. Note, undated, (1 item) (Box 12)
    Physician of U.S. Revolution. Note (ANS). Autograph signature sample.
  - Sue, Pierre, 1739-1816. Papers, 1780-1782, (2 items) (Box 12)
    French physician, surgeon and librarian. Note (ANS) to M. Caccia.
  - Day, Georgia. Letter, 1864 July 24, (2 items) (Box 12)
    Letter from a resident of Blackshear [?] to a Dr. James S. Sullivan, sent by her servant Jane, thanking him for the loan of a book to her son Edward. Probably Dr. James Swan Sullivan (1809-1874), who practiced in Savannah.
  - Swaim, William. Letter, 1830, Mar. 4, (1 item) (Box 12)
    Noted quack doctor. Letter (ALS). Assures the Major that though his panacea may or may not be of service to his daughter, it will surely do no injury to her.
  - Swieten, Gerard, Freiherr van, 1700-1772. Note, 1765, Dec. 15, (1 item) (Box 12)
    Dutch physician; personal physician and advisor to Empress Maria Theresa. Note (ANS). Reviews A. M. Salvini's Italian translation of Xenophon of Ephesus, "Di Senofonte Efesio degli Amori di Abrocome e d'Anzia", sent to the Empress Maria Theresa by the Chancellery of Hungary. Condemns the essay appended to the second edition of the volume, Cicalata sopra una certa curiosa statuetta, as "tresí impudique". Note is evidence of Swieten's function as censor to the Empress' library. A typed transcript and an English translation are available.
  - Swift, Samuel. Papers, 1776-1782, (2 items) (Box 12)
    Physician of Philadelphia. Holograph documents, signed. Swift's accounts against Jonathan Hufty (1778) and against Jacob Laughlin (1776-1779). On the reverse of each account, Justice of the Peace William Rush notes Swift's sworn testimony that accounts have not been paid (1782).
  - Tait, Lawson, 1845-1899. Papers, 1887-1895, (4 items) (Box 12)
    British surgeon and gynecologist. Two letters (ALS) to an unnamed American surgeon, in which Tait claims to have been misquoted; a newspaper clipping, which refers to accusations against Tait by Dr. E. W. Cushing; and a pamphlet by Tait, which informs the members of the council of the British Medical Society that the charges brought against him by Dr. Ernest Hart are false.
  - Tanchou, Stanislas, 1791-1850. Note, [1817], Apr. 26, (1 item) (Box 12)
    French physician. Note (ANS).
  - Tardieu, Ambroise, 1818-1879. Note, 1861, Feb. 20, (1 item) (Box 12)
    French physician and writer on medical jurisprudence. Note (ANS).
  - Tarnier, Stéphane, 1828-1897. Note, 1864, Oct. 31, (1 item) (Box 12)
    French obstetrician. Note (ANS).
  - Taylor, Charles. Letter, 1812, Nov. 18, (1 item) (Box 12)
    Letter (ALS). Invites Hume to pay a call. Refers to a Sir Robert Crawford.
  - Taylor, George B. Letter, 1830, Dec. 27, (1 item) (Box 12)
    New York physician. Letter (ALS). Taylor writes to Remsen, a banker, seeking a loan to start him in his profession and reviews his financial history.
  - Teale, T. Pridgin(Thomas Pridgin), 1831-1923. Letter, 1906, Apr. 10, (1 item) (Box 12)
    British surgeon. Letter (ALS). Concurs with Rolleston's opinion that publication of Teale's and Allbutt's paper on the surgical treatment of tuberculous glands is unnecessary at the present time.
  - Terrade, __. Note, [1803], Feb., (1 item) (Box 12)
    Physician of Bruxelles. Note (ANS).
  - Terrillon, O. (Octave Roche Simon), 1844-1895. Note, [Before 1895], (1 item) (Box 12)
    French surgeon. Note (ANS). Sets a time to meet the next day.
  - Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863. Letter, 1855, Dec. 3, (1 item) (Box 12)
    English novelist. Letter (ALS) thanking Dexter for the attention and care he received during an attack of fever while on his second tour of the United States.
  - Thauraux, __. Document, 1791, Nov. 12, (1 item) (Box 12)
    French physician. Autograph document, signed by Thauraux, for the receipt of seventy-two livres from the estate of M. Guilhier.
  - Theorell, Hugo. Manuscript, undated, (1 item) (Box 12)
    Swedish biochemist, born 1903; received 1955 Nobel Prize for Physiology or Medicine. Manuscript (AMS), unsigned. Incomplete manuscript of a study on enzymes and enzyme activation.
  - Thibault, Jean Charles. Certificate, [1797, Mar.], (1 item) (Box 12)
    French surgeon and soldier. Certifies Thibault as Surgeon, Third Class, with the Seventh Regiment of the Light Cavalry. Signed by the Inspector-Generals of the "Service de Santé des Armées", including J. F. Coste, P. Bayen, and N. Heurteloup.
  - Thomas, H. Leigh. Letter, [1800s?], (1 item) (Box 12)
    Physician. Letter (ALS). Prescribes a course of treatment for tumors, including the application of leeches.
  - Thomas, Theodore Gaillard, 1832-1903. Papers, circa 1878-1882, (6 items) (Box 12)
    New York obstetrician and gynecologist. Letters (ALS) and manuscript, signed. Letters from Thomas to Robert P. Harris, of Philadelphia, statistician of cases of Caesarean section and extra-uterine pregnancy in New York City and its environs. Manuscript, signed, appears to be a questionnaire sent by Harris and filled out by Thomas on a case of gastro-hysterotomy.
  - Thomassin, Jean-François, 1750-1828. Certificate, [1796, Mar.], (1 item) (Box 12)
    French surgeon and soldier. Certifies Thomassin as Surgeon in Chief with the Army of the Rhine and Moselle. Signed by members of the "Conseil de Santé", including J. F. Coste, P. Bayen, and N. Saucerotte.